# Vincent Walker

London SW19 | 07796 604 660 | vincethewalker@gmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | Website | GitHub

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE** -

Perceptive, proactive, self-taught Ruby on Rails developer with a commitment to creation of clean, efficient, and accessible code in a functional framework throughout the development lifecycle. A reliable individual with genuine integrity and a strong background in client and stakeholder management, sales, marketing, budget and performance management, providing invaluable all round business expertise.

# **CORE COMPETENCIES -**

- Web Development
   Quality Assu
  - Team Leadership & Development

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS** =

- ❖ Java Script ❖ Ruby on Rails ❖ HTML ❖ CSS ❖ Bootstrap ❖ ActiveRecord
- $\diamond$  PostgreSQL
    $\diamond$  GitHub
    $\diamond$  Heroku
    $\diamond$  TDD
    $\diamond$  ActionCable

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS -**

- From learning to code in 2017, rapidly progressed to creating several original APIs
  - Business Den: A SaaS application providing an interface between investors and start-up entrepreneurs
  - The Blogger: A simple RESTful API sharing photos and blogs
  - Project App: A project sharing app
- Wrote functional, unit and integration tests using RSpec, GitHub as Repositary and Heroku for production
- Built a bespoke SaaS application (Business Den) using Devise as a User authentication solution, Sendgrid for email integration functionality and STRIPE API for payment authentication using a creditCard (Business Den), AWS S3 for Image storage.
- Developed a Web Sockets Platform, a Recipe Sharing API (My Recipes) using Rails's ActionCable

#### **CAREER SUMMARY** -

#### **BUSINESS SYSTEMS DEVELOPER - HOSTELLING INTERNATIONAL**

June 2019 - Current

- Been working to Redevelop the Front End, Involved in the planning to move the platform from a Sinatra based frame work
  to a Rails one.
- Gained valuable experience in CSS SASS, Ruby Debugging as well as Agile working

#### WEB DEVELOPER / RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - CDC GLOBAL

November 2018 - May 2019

Working Freelance with CDC Global to create and develop the company Web Site.

### **RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER**

March 2017 - October 2018

- Developed my skills HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Ruby on Rails This included Active Record Data Base Migrations with SQL lite and POSTRES, Git Hub, Heroku.
- Created 3 API's, 'Business Den', 'MyRecipe', 'The Blogger' (https://vincethewalker.com)

#### **AYMES INERNATIONAL:** NHS Partnership Manager

Sep 2016 - Feb 2017

 Worked to gain market access for a range of Oral Nutritional Supplements with NHS Medicines Management, Community Dietitians and Hospital Dietitians across 30 CCG's in London and Berkshire

# **GLAXOSMITHKLINE:** Vaccines Key Account Manager

2004 - 2016

- In line with GSK's new Digital Strategy, took on Digital Team Lead role, collaborating with Marketing to develop new team website to drive 2 way communication and share information between sales and brand teams
- Collaborated in developing GSK vaccines on-line ordering Platform which enabled healthcare professionals to place their orders on-line in addition to using traditional channels.
- Acting Regional Business Manager In 2010, to cover sickness, supported the team in implementing strategy, regularly liaising between management and brand teams

### **EARLIER CAREER** =

JANSSEN CILAG (SOUTH AFRICA): Specialist Medical Representative HART LTD (SOUTH AFRICA): Sales Representative SOUTH AFRICAN ARMY MEDICAL SERVICES: Operational Medic

## **EDUCATION** =

Diploma in Sales Management - Damelin College, South Africa Secondary School - Damelin College, South Africa